Darius Elphick

CONTACT Information

59 Henry Doulton Drive, Tooting Bec, London, SW17 6DB. Mobile: +44(0)7792526693 E-mail: hi@tenaciousdarius.dev LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/dariuselphick

Personal Profile

Senior Developer and Team Lead with over ten years of experience building and maintaining commercial web and mobile applications in the media and transport industries. Experience working across the full software stack as well as managing development teams and product management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development:

- HTML5, CSS3 and Responsive Web Design
- OO Javascript, ReactJS, Redux, JQuery and AngularJS
- Node.js and Express
- Browser Support including IE 8 11, Edge, Crhome, Firefox and Safari
- Accessibility Standards including Semantic HTML and ARIA Tags
- Design Patterns for building large, scalable web applications including MVVM,
 MVC and React Redux

Test Driven Development: Experience working in teams practicing TDD using unit testing tools including Mocha, Jest, PhantomJS and Karma.

Web Services: Designing and Integrating with REST and SOAP web services.

DevOps: AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, Route 53, CloudWatch, IAM), Docker, Network Management and Security.

Version Control: Git and Mercurial

Methodologies: Experience working in Agile teams using SCRUM, SAFE, FDD and XP

Professional Experience

The Trainline, London.

Engineering Team Lead

Apr. 2019 to Oct. 2019

- Managed a team of seven Frontend Developers working on the company's mobile web product, including day to day management of timelines and prioritisation, mentorship, setting objectives and performance review.
- Some React and Redux development.
- Introduced new testing and release processes to improve quality, working closely with other leads and the QA team.
- Provided day-to-day SCRUM team leadership.

BBC Global News, London.

Senior Front End Developer

Apr. 2017 to Mar. 2019

• Developed and maintained the BBC Features Websites as well as other commercial projects.

- Managed a team of two other Front End Developers working on a new PWA version of the sites using React and Redux.
- Applied technical and product management experience to portfolio of innovative projects combining commercial and editorial requirements gathered at Innovation Summit in New York with cutting edge technologies including AR, VR and Gamification.

BBC Studios, London.

Senior Front End Developer

Aug. 2015 to Mar. 2017

- Worked with several teams throughout the BBC on development and release of the BAFTA-nominated Sir David Attenborough's Story of Life, a cross-platform app for accessing archived nature documentaries.
- Recruited for several roles within the team, including writing job descriptions, reviewing CVs and conducting interviews.

Web Developer

Aug. 2014 to Aug. 2015

• Migrated all BBC Features sites to a new platform build in house. Contributed to the design of the new framework, called Glaze.

SyQic Limited, Gerrards Cross and Kuala Lumpur.

Technical and Development Specialist

Jul. 2012 to Aug. 2014

- As part of an international team, built the universal, localised iOS app for Yoonic, the company's primary IPTV product. Designed robust app structure via the MVC-N design pattern.
- Also worked on the web-version of Yoonic, built using AngularJS, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Built and integrated with REST and SOAP Web Services.

Aberystwyth University, Aberystwyth.

Computer Science Advisor

Sept. 2011 to May 2012

• Advised fellow students on their programming assignments and provided debugging support.

Cyngor Gwynedd Council, Caernarfon.

Programmer/Analyst on Work Experience

July 2011 to Sept. 2011

• Specified, designed and prototyped a multilingual iPhone app for displaying municipal information provided by a SOAP web service.

Programmer/Analyst on Work Experience June 2009 to Sept. 2010

- Worked with a small team on the ongoing development and support of a large scale Siebel CRM deployment.
- Liaised on-site with project stakeholders when performing requirements analysis and presenting completed projects.

EDUCATION

Aberystwyth University, Aberystwyth.

Sept. 2007 to June 2012

MEng (1st Class Hons) Software Engineering

Additional Information

Other Skills: Fluent Welsh speaker.

Other Achievements: Passionate about good mental health and fundraise for the Mental Health Foundation. Raised £1,102 through bake sales and sponsorship to run the Hackney Half Marathon in 2017. Followed this up April 2019 by running the London Marathon and raising £2,326.

Interests: Some of my interests include video games, reading and travel. Within the past year, the best game I've played is Civilization VI, the best books I've read are Born to Run by Christopher McDougall and Salt Fat Acid Heat by Samin Nosrat, and the best destination I've visited was Milford Sound, New Zealand. I'm also a keen baker.

Referees

References available on request.